Alex Mansfield

Full Stack Software Developer

Contact









portfolio ajmansfield0@gmail.com

Bristol, UK

mansfieldalex

alexjames4

I am an empathetic, considerate and highly analytical individual with a drive for learning who is currently seeking an opportunity to begin a career as a Software Developer.

Having always had a passion for mathematics, problem-solving and technology I am searching for a career where I can continue to develop skills generated during my time on iO Academy's Full Stack Bootcamp whilst having a positive and meaningful impact to the world around me.

Interests

Game Jams

I have started to develop a game on the theme of 'SCALE' with a friend as part of the Itch.io 'Game Off 2023' using the Godot Engine

Cycling

I am a keen cyclist and love exploring the countryside on my bike scouting out the amazing views and pubs we have in the surrounding area.

Record Collecting

Recently I have acquired a record player and have spent many joyful hours expanding my personal collection.

Spending Time with my Dog

I have a 2 and a half year old Sprocker Spaniel called Cinder. She is a little chaos potato, who hates pigeons and loves leaves.

Music Festivals

I've been to many music festivals over the years including Glastonbury, Y Not and Womad.

Projects

Academy Portal Application

For this project, I had the chance to work with a legacy code base that has been worked on by all the previous cohorts of iO Academy. I utilised the Slim Framework to assist with the MVC architecture to add a feature to the courses page which allowed for visual differentiation between upcoming and future courses as well as a toggle button to show/hide completed courses. To do this I had to combine and utilise all of my HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL skills I have acquired so far.

Live Link GitHub

Project Management API

For this project, as part of a team of 4 at iO Academy, I helped to design an Object-Oriented PHP API to work with a pre-built React front end so that projects were displayed detailing the people and tasks assigned to each with the correct success or error response message being displayed in line with a specified API documentation.

Live Link GitHub

Email Client Application

As part of a team at iO Academy, I helped to create an email client following a specified design which allowed the user to compose and display emails and signify whether they had been read/unread. This combined and improved my HTML, CSS and JavaScript proficiency through usage of the React and Bootstrap Frameworks. Live Link GitHub

Certifications

Agile Professional Jul Certification 2023

iO Academy

Full UK Driving Feb License 2009

Skills

HTML CSS

JavaScript TypeScript

PHP MySQL

C# React

Slim MongoDB

Node.js Git

Employment History

Limber Oct 2023 – present

Part-time kitchen work

Electric Bear Brewing Co. Jan 2018 – Mar 2022

Assistant Head Brewer

Whilst working at EB I demonstrated my ability to work effectively in a team to a tight schedule, ensuring that multiple tasks were completed correctly and simultaneously by the production team ensuring that the final product was of the high standard that stakeholders expected.

The Malago Oct 2015 – Dec 2017

Sous Chef

During my time at the Malago I demonstrated my ability to multitask under high levels of pressure and my capacity to learn and implement new skills.

Arbor Ales Sep 2014 – Sep

2015

Brewer

RPS Group Aug 2013 – Aug

2014

Graduate Safety Case Consultant

Education

Full Stack Software Developer Jul 2023 – Oct 2023

Bootcamp

iO Academy, Bath

A 16-week bootcamp where I have learnt a range of different front-end and back-end programming languages through taught theory and subsequent application of the theory through a range of individual and team-based projects.

Secondary PGCE with Physics Sep 2022 – May

Specialism 2023

Bath Spa University

MEng Chemical EngineeringSep 2009 – Jul 2013University of Birmingham2:1 (with Hons)

A Levels & GCSEs Sep 2002 – Jul 2009

The Blue School, Wells

A Levels: AAA Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry AS Levels: A - Further Mathematics, B - Biology

GCSEs: 10 GCSEs

A* - English Literature, Music, Maths A – History, Chemistry, Physics,

Biology, English Language, Citizenship B – Economics

ı				